hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is Jeremy
Krakowski and we haven't met yet I help
coaches trainers mentors authors and
speakers scale their businesses to 20 to
40 000 per month and Beyond using paid
advertising funnels copywriting and any
way of getting clients through the
internet I'm your guy now listen today
I'm excited to introduce you to somebody
that I've known for a while her name is
Venice Robbins she's absolutely
incredible when it comes to the mindset
of what it takes to help you get unstuck
and so Venice welcome to the podcast how
are you today I am great it's so
exciting and awesome to be with you
Jeremiah thank you yeah I'm listen I'm
honored and glad that you said yes to be
here so
um tell everybody who's listening to
this just a little bit about you and how
you got started uh in this work and and
what you do and what you help people
with
sure
okay cool my name's Venice hi everyone
and I as Jeremiah said I am an expert in
personal growth I got started years ago
before personal growth was a thing it
was like over 20 years ago and uh my
starting point was honestly I was
miserable in my own life and pretending
to be happy and I wasn't and I I really
came across personal growth and it
radically altered the quality of my life
and I think the biggest thing that I got
was I have a say in my life
and I lived as a victim my whole life
and to really get it at my core that I
actually had to say was was
revolutionary so uh I leaned in deeply
to personal growth and fast forward I uh
you know gosh I'm a life coach I've
worked for a world renowned life
coaching company my background is
actually nutrition I'm a nutritionist
yeah
I already got like 10 questions I want
to ask you this is amazing
sure like like into like where you're
doing right now and how are you helping
people today
well the thing is uh eight years ago I
got really sick and I could not work I
had all the symptoms of fibromyalgia
that's a whole other chapter which I
won't get into now but I found myself in
a place where I couldn't work like in
traditional work and I thought about man
you know what what I want to do for the
next 25 years of my life and that was
the beginning of
pursuing something that I didn't know
what it looked like it was very like all
I know was I wanted to serve women and I
wanted to do it in a larger scale and so
my brother told me about this thing
called Facebook he was like you should
check out this thing called Facebook I'd
never heard of it I started an account I
came across Sandy kurkowski who was my
first business yes your mom my first
business coach and that was uh the big
that was a huge part of a foundation of
what does it look like to be on the
online space and serve people well and
also be able to make money so that's
what I've been up to for eight years now
and it has been such an incredible
journey I'm on my social media you can
find me at Venice
um that's really simple
v-e-n-n-i-e-c-e and these days like I
find I'm really interested in working
with women who struggle with
perfectionism low self-esteem and fear
and what I do is I show women how to
overcome so that they're actually in
action designing a life they love like
really in courageous action so I have a
couple of life coaching groups online
and I love it it's a lot of fun yeah so
yeah help me help me understand a little
bit here
um when you say perfectionism women that
struggle with that how does that
manifest and and look in people's lives
how does even would you say
perfectionism is a a form of
self-sabotage
um
I think it could definitely be so like
perfectionism is it there's actually
like different kinds of perfectionism
how it shows up I think a real common
one is what we would call the Taskmaster
okay which is a constant evaluation
there's the pessimist critic for
perfectionist so perfectionism can look
a number of different ways even being a
caregiver
can be can show up as perfectionism and
the bottom line is it's where we are
driven to do something whether it's
caring for others if it's
um you know
demanding that we live in a certain
standard where there's Freedom that's
the common yeah and I think as we've
lived our lives like that for so many
years I myself am a recovered
perfectionist right it's draining it's
exhausting it's it's almost like you
can't control it too like it feels it's
uncontrollable
yeah and one of the things in the
coaching that I'm I'm doing is really
distinguish it it's not necessarily all
of who we are but it's a part of who we
are right so in coaching we can help
people distinguish that part of who we
are and it gives room when we do it with
love and compassion and actually
consider that the perfectionist part of
us can actually help us
is talking about is there's um there's a
practice called ifs internal family
systems sometimes called Parts work uh
if you've been following my mom she
talks about it to uh Gabby Bernstein has
literally shifted her whole entire
business around Parts work even and
she's getting certified in that and and
so Venice talk a little bit more about
that about how a
the thing that we think is what's
stopping us from succeeding though it
was a success strategy that we built up
in ourselves through life experiences
um how does that work to where somebody
because I want to I want to Circle back
around to who we're talking to here
coaches course graders trainers and
mentors that they want to make multiple
six figures in a business so that's who
our audience is so they have a goal that
requires a level of for lack of a better
word performance in their life to do
certain activities and they might be
stuck from doing those each day or
struggling to even launch or false start
maybe they get an idea and then they get
halfway ready to launch and then it
never seems to things never seem to
leave the idea stage yeah what would you
kind of say if you kind of would bring
this all together for them to help them
I would say two things and this is gonna
sound really simple it is and it takes
some practice the first thing I would
say is that who we really are like in
our true self our true identity is
extremely courageous confident creative
connected and calm like that is truly
who we really are okay okay so there's
actually there though what if the
evidence in your life is showing that
you are the exact opposite of all those
things
I'm you're right one step ahead of me
so I'm going to give you that's what a
lot of people think they're like I am
not any of those and I'm not gonna step
into toxic positivity and try to fake it
till you make it and think I am totally
I'm gonna give you a demonstration this
is the way I do in my coaching it's
perfect
let's consider just consider this is who
we really are okay okay and then there's
this part of us who is not that
maybe this is part of us that's like
you're a loser you're a failure you
can't do it you know and when in that
part of us because we actually have them
collapsed we actually think that that
part of us that tells us you're an idiot
I mean I've heard everything okay you're
stupid oh you can't do right you know
why would you even mindwise you're a
criminal because I was arrested so many
times from drinking and all of that and
so anytime I do anything wrong it goes
back into like the police mode yeah mine
was you'll never have what you want
you'll never have what you and it just
it was it's the thing that always
stopped me wow so I would go so far I
would dream but then it was like that
part of me who felt real and I think
that if there's one thing that people
could take away from this conversation
is to consider that who we really are is
all those things connected courageous
creative
Etc and there's that part of us that
really stops us and as a practice it's
really distinct distinguishing that
they're separate so here's what that
could look like okay is
being willing to get curious and
compassionate about this part that stops
US
um just consider that it comes from
somewhere it's just like you were saying
Jeremiah with yours where I'm a criminal
mine was I can't ever have what I want
right it comes from somewhere and as we
can create some space to be curious and
even compassionate towards that part of
us because it's not really who we are
it's created as some kind of survival
effort protection and even the practice
of saying you know what I hear you
I hear you that little girl that's nine
years old that told herself she can't
have what I want and I just want you to
know I'm listening
yeah and even we could take it a step
further is getting curious around you
know what are you scared of
and having that conversation with
ourselves consider we're always having
conversations with ourselves
we're always Talking to Ourselves but
it's really being able to have a
conversation with that side of us and
say and this is like a practice I coach
in is I see you I hear you I understand
and I want you to consider I'm not that
person
I'm not that criminal that's not really
who I am I'm not that nine-year-old
anymore I'm actually 50 and I've learned
a lot of ways that I can navigate my
life and I actually have made some
really great choices
I'm asking you to give me some room to
lead
and you can even come along with me can
I tell you a story real quick about that
happened yesterday
I got some questions for you on this
because I I feel like if people are
listening to this right now
um I wanna I wanna help kind of lead
them to gain a better understanding as
what you're talking about and we'll go
over some of that here tell me the story
though what was it
so this is something that really has
stopped me my whole life it's very
specific in my relationship with my
mother and it's affected my business
okay yesterday I had a conversation with
my mom I'm not going to get into the
details but there is a part of me that
has felt like I'm really all alone
and in my business I have felt like I'm
really all alone as a business owner
I've worked so hard and I didn't realize
I've not been alone I actually have a
lot of resources around me but I've
never been able to really allow those
resources to kind of assist me because
who I've been is alone so I it was a
huge breakthrough okay it's like this
week's breakthrough from doing this
practice so you have to share something
for the group too on this it's listen to
this podcast you're not alone if you're
listening to this podcast you got the
podcast Community if you comment on this
podcast on YouTube I comment back if you
go on my social media I comment back if
you connect with the niece you got both
of us right now in your corner saying
you're not alone all right keep going
yeah I love it's so true yes so I have a
conversation with my mom and I can feel
that part of me this feeling really
nervous like you've tried to talk to her
in the past and
when you try to talk to her this is how
it goes because I've been trying to have
this phrase with my mom right there you
go for years and I was able to in the
moment acknowledge I hear you and I'm
asking you to trust me wow because I
know what I'm doing in this conversation
Jeremiah everyone listening it was the
most incredible conversation I've ever
had with my mother
we cried together we we sorted some
things out
I was able to speak from a different
place I've always been speaking to my
mom from anger I've been so pissed off
at her and I I released it I said I know
you love me I'm giving up the anger I
mean she was blown away and here's the
thing this impacts my business
yep it does every time I grow and I have
more space as a person it is reflective
I have more space in my business so I
love this simple you know there's who we
really are then there is that part of us
that tells us whatever it says it stops
US it stops us from getting into action
it says if you try you're gonna fail or
it questions everything you have to have
all the hundred things lined up before
you do it because otherwise it's not
going to work that's just another part
sometimes our part is logical
[Music]
we get so the planning and the logic and
the analysis of everything that it stops
us and it's really developing as a
practice the ability to just like say
hey that's not necessarily who I am
but get curious about it and have a
conversation what are you scared of how
are you protecting me
how do you help me and when I checked in
with that part it was like well we don't
want to get hurt I don't want to get
hurt yeah
so I'm going to keep that up so I
protect you Venice so it's a simple
practice it's very powerful yeah
here's some of the questions I have
because in conversations like this with
people that might be listening to this
podcast especially if they come from
like a religious background they might
have a part of them that is resistant to
hearing some of this or misunderstanding
it like are we talking about
schizophrenia here are we talking about
demon possession are we talking about uh
Shadow work are we talking like like how
is this
different than that are related to that
in this in this whole world in
conversation
well
the person if
wait a minute are you talking about
multiple personalities
exactly disorder totally and you know
the thing is it's very helpful to do the
research okay and Dr Richard Schwartz
who is the originator you're talking
about 35 years of experience and
marriage and family therapy he has a
book called no bad parts that I highly
recommend if you're interested in this
conversation
really pick it up and that one statement
of the title of the book
challenges a lot of our world view
because we look at okay this part of me
is bad so that's why it's not successful
this part of me is bad so that's why I'm
doing things that I don't want to do
this part of me is bad and and we and we
we can notice ourselves saying that we I
even
um had hatred towards my younger self
that got arrested that drank too much
and I realized what actually brought me
into the idea of studying Parts work is
I had gone through a lot of inner
healing a lot of talk therapy a lot of
Deliverance Ministry with my church and
yet they were like okay why is this not
working right you've been through all
that too and it's and I don't and I
think that there's a place for it too as
well I really do still but this work is
is on a whole other level of saying
actually you're not bad and actually I'm
just going to go straight into the faith
side of it here it it shows us how the
father sees us
yes the Father in Heaven sees us as
there's no part of us that's bad
amen there's no part of us that is dirty
or ugly or disgusting and when we start
to see ourselves as that way it changes
everything about how we live love lead
parent and build our businesses
I want to add one thing I totally 100
agree I think one of the challenges we
have as Believers is that we we don't
really approach things like in an
integrative way we see things like Mind
Body Spirit and spirit of course people
of faith we have a heavy emphasis on
faith right the thing is what we don't
realize is we're not three compartments
the my body spirit is all one system
that's the first thing the second thing
for whatever reason hey not judging or
anything we in the church we don't have
knowledge basic knowledge about how the
mind and brain works yeah it's kind of
incomplete you know and we hear messages
about be transformed by the renewing of
our mind but even if you just have a
basic understanding of how the mind
works when you really like study
psychology there is yeah all human
beings have like different personalities
they're that's very well researched it's
established science it doesn't mean you
have like multiple personality disorders
exactly it's not the same thing it's
just having an understanding of that
this is how the creator of the universe
made our mind that's here this is by
Design how God put our operating system
together and
in fact like you're you're right the
Bible actually does talk about this I
think sometimes we can get into a
religious State of Mind of well you know
like
when I when I prayed the prayer Jesus
healed it and if I don't believe that
there's something wrong with me that
framework is still kind of operating in
this kind of performance for love based
if I do then I will get if I do good
then I'm safe if I don't do right then
I'll get punished or I won't get a
reward things like that and and what
I've found is is that really taking a
look at okay how does the Mind work even
from a scientific standpoint what I love
is that the Bible and science don't
conflict each other they actually
support each other yes it's so good I
love it oh the other thing I was gonna
say is that you know I've said the
Prayer of Healing I've done inner
healing like Ministry Deliverance
Ministry Retreats I've gone to my
husband and I and what I really
discovered is that yeah when we go and
we say the prayers it's not that nothing
happens the prayers are the beginning of
a season
that's really good we pray we get an
agreement with heaven we believe in what
the scriptures say and then it's almost
like God's like okay you ready you're in
partnership with me let's go well yeah
you said was was one of the most
powerful statements I've heard in the
last year
can you say that again when we say the
prayers what does it do it starts a
season
yeah it begins a whole
city where
Creator knows all about us the Creator
knows when we're ready
we're not sorry it's like my brain is
like
so it's it's participating in our own
healing we are not oh we are working out
our healing
we're walking it out and I'm gonna say
okay I'm gonna I'm gonna walk away from
uh pornography and then I'm logging into
a site late at night and like like I
have to still show up at a certain point
in that to walk out what I've prayed and
declared and am living for my life and
for my marriage
and uh now this brings in one other
important element and I believe this
with all my heart we're not designed to
do it alone
um God himself is community the godhead
God the Father God the son God the
spirit right we are designed to live
grow and thrive in community so wherever
what in the seasons in all seasons of
life it's really designed like I believe
God's heart is do it in community that's
where you that's where the juice in life
is and what I love about we both have
online communities right so I love you
know having online community because
people can connect from anywhere in the
world and we can be connected and we
have a community here with the grow Your
Life podcast and our coaching group
interestingly enough you're listening
it's not a it's not a Christian or
Church community it's actually we have
we have a number of people like that
that don't share the same Faith as me
but we're operating and learning all
this stuff together because these
strategies work for everybody
which is amazing so here's something I
want to I want to say you you said
something at the beginning that you
discovered when you learned this it
helped you no longer sabotage you're
able to open up your voice it allowed
you to design your life and have a say
in your life and I find that that's a
big thing for me growing up I never felt
that I had a say in life I was taught
delayed obedience is Disobedience and if
I don't ask how high when I'm asked to
jump It's Disobedience and that I will
be punished physically emotionally and
spiritually if I don't operate that way
so that way of living is what I lived in
19 years of my life till I moved out of
my parents house and so that was how I
was wired is that I have no say in my
life yeah and and and and which is crazy
because that's the complete opposite of
you know those of you that know my mom
like like she looking back she's like
yeah that I would never have raised you
that way you know if I had known right
and we and we've since healed and grown
and our relationship but what would you
say to somebody because I know that
there's people who listen to this that
they feel that way I got no say in my
life I have no um I know what I want I
see it but it's impossible
I would say again
consider
allowing yourself some room to get
curious about that a lot of times we
don't bring curiosity and we don't bring
compassion
yeah you know a lot of times like I want
to kill that side of me I wanna I wanna
obliterate that well okay here's the
reality probably that part of you that
side of you has been around for a very
long time it's probably a part of the
entire neural hard wiring of your brain
yeah and it's funny I found myself even
some of my content I've said that before
and I'm starting to as I'm learning to
say okay maybe we need to embrace it
listen to it not kill it
that has been one of my biggest things
from like takeaways and breakthroughs
yeah 22 is I've been trying to erase
things that are not erasable because
they're literally hard wiring in my
brain I'm not that's not going to change
I mean I guess it's nothing's impossible
some massive Miracle but probably it's
not going to happen what I can do and to
answer your question for those who are
listening is you could first of all
consider that the good news the bad news
bad news it's not going to go away good
news is you could get curious about why
you do that what it serves the purpose
in your life
yeah you could actually create some kind
of like this is powerful collaboration
like for me my life with this
conversation by the way I hope you do
yeah so here's the fruit of it soon
amen what I do and this is what I teach
my clients is I'm like okay in my mind
it's like I have my true who I am and my
identity who I am in Christ and then
there were these parts of me that have
been around for a long time so I'm like
okay we're all doing this together
and I really intentional to be aware
there's sometimes like even before I
came on the podcast I could feel I was
nervous and I was checking in with
myself I was like okay what's there and
I could hear oh what if you screw it up
what if it doesn't go well you know what
if you say something stupid and then
it's so amazing just so you know
the best episodes ever thank you I was
just like okay I hear you and let's just
do this together we've got this you know
so it's so much compassion for my
Humanity I think I work with women for a
living and the biggest thing I see is
that there's two pitfalls one we don't
give ourselves room for our humanness in
our growth the second is we think just
because we did something for a week
we're done
growth is a season it takes time you
know to kind of like get on your feet
look it's like almost like walking you
know you're gonna have a baby soon you
and Abigail you're so excited Dan and
then he's gonna fall and then he's gonna
stand and then he's gonna walk and
that's time and it's the same way for us
for the people like you're like oh my
gosh that's sabotager I know I have that
Vision but it always keeps coming up
give yourself some room and begin to
take on transforming your relationship
to the sabotager yeah and you could
great let's do this together because I'm
always going to be afraid
but I don't have to try to obliterate it
I could still move forward and the other
thing is having coaches and mentors
because we as coaches and mentors we're
highly trained we're not perfect we're
in our own Journey we've just trekked
the way I'm not perfect at all y'all
just so you all know Denise isn't no no
coaches if you meet a coach that claims
they're perfect I'd run
yes yeah or they have it all handled you
know or like somebody got it all figured
out yeah
I'm always like when was your last
breakthrough if your last breakthrough
was 20 years ago I'm like well growth is
an ongoing process
Denise Robbins dropping bombs with
Denise Robbins
that's it so yeah you know it coaches
and mentors because we could you shared
some things with me that were so
powerful as my as my business coach I'm
like I didn't see it I totally get it or
you're confirming Something in My Heart
I've known oh yeah I want to get some
coaching from you here right now on this
call we're just gonna I'm just gonna be
selfish here because I think being more
selfish is actually helpful in our
businesses
um is you know as taking advantage of
every situation that you can in a way
that honors and serves everybody else
that's how I see it if I'm taking
advantage of a situation I wanted to
honor and serve everybody around me and
so like this week we use the group they
helped write my copy for that now I'm
not going to do that all the time but it
was it was a fun exercise for everybody
so I've got a question for you here
there was and and it's funny she might
be listening to this podcast episode the
lady I'm talking about
so I'm going to be a little careful as
to how I bring it so she um
I had a lady yesterday write me was
convinced that I was a scammer a
fraudster
um that I was still stole her money
stole her credit card
um because she paid me 17 for an upsell
on an offer on our website and she wrote
me and said I need you to video call me
to prove this and then she started
threatening me and she started sending
me these threats that she's going to
shut down my page and my social media
and I did not react in a way that I
would like I reacted in a way that I'm
not proud of I actually immediately
video called her and I said I said first
off I am the real Jeremy kakowski and
you're banned from ever doing anything
with my business and it was just like
you know because I'm just like I can't
have somebody that is threatening me
when they're only sending Seventeen
Dollars around me in my space now that
is a boundary that I've created for my
business if somebody's listening to this
right now uh I don't respond well to
threats but here's the thing is I I
don't respond well to threats and I
think that's something that I'm starting
to to realize is like if somebody's
threatening me especially if it's not
true
it's more so if it's not true if you
threaten me or upset because it is true
I tend to shrink back
if you're threatening me and it's not
true I become this roaring lion that I
just like I forget that I'm a Christian
I like I I say things that like I look
back and I'm like oh I could have done
that better and so like what would you
say to become curious about in that
moment
well
there's two things I would say one is
it's really great that you're aware like
it sounds like you're not helping me at
all so yeah
I would I'm sure you Holly's been kind
of personal time of reflection or
meditation or prayer yeah yeah and those
times I would begin to explore that I
have like a little practice on my iPhone
I have like I collect Parts yeah I'm in
prayer I have a specific time of focus
because I made a decision in that moment
when that happened I need to kill that
part of me and now here's what's crazy
for eight hours after that I struggled
the entire day I literally passed out on
the couch for two hours I almost felt
like I went through a death a little bit
and I and I now I've been trying to
explore that part of me and he's not
showing up
yeah so then what I if so I would first
try to get present and one they call it
Trail heads and um ifs but see if you
can get present in your body to how you
felt because feelings or Sensations are
ways that we can I'll do it in my
private time not right now yeah
present to that part and the key is
Jeremiah is how we come at it and it's
if you can
really Practice coming with curiosity or
compassion letting that part of me know
it's safe to show up even though I
threatened to kill him yeah
I'm being around you yeah it's hard for
me and then getting curious around how
do you help me
or what's it this is another question I
ask what's it like being you
um wow and you know I'm starting to feel
it even while we're talking this is
amazing
it's incredible
so that would be something you could do
and then just get really curious and say
I hear you I see you and you could ask
for some space like wow you know if
something happens I'm asking to give me
some space so I can deal with what is
happening in the present moment it helps
if you can do it when you're not in the
situation right when you're in a
situation your whole central nervous
system is like yeah
on alert yeah
yeah it's hard to come you know until
you can kind of sort through it offline
I had something I won't get into the
detail it's kind of not necessarily
appropriate for now but I had a very
traumatizing situation when I was in my
20s in college and just recently when I
was in uh Colorado visiting family I had
a moment where I had a panic attack
because my brain felt like I was in what
happened right and I froze and through
the practicing like what I'm saying I
was able to pause and say okay Venice
you're not in college and what's
happening is not happening right now
then I removed myself the room and I
went to the lobby of the hotel and I
just sat and I was I breathed a little
and then I just said okay you're safe
you're not in danger
and I could feel my whole body just
calming down and I just gave myself room
and then I was like okay let's try this
again
let's go back to that room
and let's see how we do wow and what
I've learned is I'm still going to feel
a little anxious but I can give myself
room like yesterday with my mom I was
really scared to talk to my mom so I
stopped on the side of the road I was
like okay we're just gonna get to the
driveway
and we're gonna see how we feel then
we're gonna go in the house and we're
gonna get in the car and go to the
restaurant and we're gonna see how we
feel then and then we're gonna and I was
playing it out I was like okay that
scared part of me who was like it's not
safe because you know how it always goes
yeah it was incredible I was able to
take it in little pieces
in little pieces let's go through it
that's awesome that's the power of being
aware and altering the relationship we
have to those parts so with you I would
just recommend you get curious about it
and yeah offline and you'll notice
you'll have more
um ability to interrupt I've already
I've already gotten a little bit curious
even in the last two minutes I've just
been like
thinking about it and I remember for the
first time I remember where it came up
five years ago
um I remember you know and if I go back
and find that part like what age is it
of me that really and I think maybe it
was in the last five years that
is willing to say no
yeah and willing to set a boundary
because it's not afraid like doesn't
want to be walked all over
yes but has maybe set that boundary in
The Not So best way and then has gotten
hurt
yeah in a previous situation where maybe
I was threatened or felt threatened yeah
um and and responded in that way oh I'm
even thinking through so my my wife
actually said something very interesting
she said you haven't
sounded that way since you lived in
Kansas City
and so I'm thinking
I just remembered I'm thinking back to a
time in Kansas City where
um and this is part of how this goes
everybody if you're watching this
actively is you'll notice behavior that
you're doing now and then you're going
to think of a time where you did it in
the past and that feeling you get
present to that feeling and you're able
to do that I have found a very
interesting ability to get present with
the feelings while staying active in my
outward self
and like like I'm engaging with the
podcast but internally I'm actually
pretty present with that feeling right
now yes um yes it takes you a little
while to get to that's what I found a
lot of my teaching comes from is being
able to do that
um because I'll even get active to some
of the parts of my clients with empathy
a little bit and be able to answer some
of that based off of my own experiences
and so I'm thinking back to a time I had
a realtor tell me that she was um gonna
steal the keys to my house if I fired
her and I was 500 miles away from her
and I and I stepped into that part of me
in that moment and
um said the sent the police after her to
go get my keys and so literally like
that was the part that showed up yeah
yesterday it was that same like you know
protecting my family type of it was a
protector I'm seeing that as that way
it's the don't mess with my family don't
mess with my living type of thing and
but like you know this lady was was just
scared she was scared that she was gonna
be taken advantage of she was scared
that I was a scammer she was worried of
that
um now at the same time I think it's
best that she not engaged with our
business I think maybe even if she
reaches out to you and works through
some of that would be incredible that'd
be amazing you know getting some therapy
getting some of that help so I'm not
going to mention her by name
um but like this is an experience and if
you're a coach or a course grader online
you're going to have these experiences
with people you know I I understand
there might be some people that the fact
that I responded that way ruins my
credibility with them I'm working on
this myself I'm not perfect you're here
may be very vulnerable with you about
one of the one of the things that I
almost hide sometimes don't even bring
to the table but but I believe that God
has given me an opportunity to talk with
people about this because it's something
that's hindering them as well
that's awesome I think definitely there
is
um room for creating boundaries I've
learned that in my business everyone has
an opinion on social media and I have
just certain rules like you can't cuss
at me you can't you don't get to
threaten me and you don't get to be mean
to me I would have people's horrible
messages and I mean I it's just like
they're not it's a they're seeing
through a distortion right and um
experience in their beliefs yeah and I'm
like hey I got it I heard you and I just
want to let you know you don't get to
speak to me that way and I'm Banning you
from my page
the experience
yeah and I tell her I hear you uh and I
and I go back and forth
yeah yeah I am quitting this month
it's great yeah tomorrow afternoon today
today
minus 24. yeah because I'm like I'm like
okay yesterday like I said I was
quitting this Behavior a week ago and
now this you know like but like I I had
somebody this morning even was like you
know I completely disagree with you that
doesn't apply to me and I almost went
back and forth instead I made a post on
my social media and shared the post with
her again I don't even need to do that
but yeah
one thing that also helps is I you know
I love the definition of compassion in
ifs it's one of the definitions is uh
is empathizing with others knowing that
when they experience healing they will
be able to release their own burdens
yeah to me I really have been able to
keep that in mind that when when people
are being like their parts are coming
out I can say you know what I choose to
be empathetic I don't feel sorry for
them but I choose to be empathetic
because they're carrying their own
hurt and it's projecting and I know that
when they choose to get into their
healing season they're going to be free
and I it's made a huge difference for me
to be able to hold space even for and
have true compassion for others so I
think there's really a lot to be said
about you know it takes something
because it's like we are human we're
gonna have a reaction but then it's
pausing uh and noticing what part of us
is coming up and then also choosing I'm
choosing to be compassionate but also
holding people accountable like you know
it doesn't work for you to cuss me out
right yeah we don't do that here yeah
and I'm not going to go back and forth
but I hear what you're saying or
invalidate and to invalidate me I just
like exactly
your experience and mine don't have to
be the same doesn't make mine invalid or
yours invalid exactly yeah that's great
here's something that so I made this
post this morning it's a photo of my
wife and I standing on our steps I don't
know I saw it yeah and I wanted to kind
of close here today with that is that
from what you just said we need to give
ourselves compassion and I see it as the
compassion that we would give our
ourselves as a child The Compassion that
we would give ourselves as even a
newborn baby
yes and that's a big one because we look
at okay we're born as a baby perfect in
every way
and then we have this belief that we
become not that that we transform into
not that over time and I would challenge
you today to start to see yourself and
other people as perfect as how they are
as not needing to change and so I wrote
this post I'm just going to read it to
you my baby boy he's going to be born in
three or four weeks
my baby boy sorry I'm crying
my baby boy is good enough in fact he is
perfect and he always will be
there's nothing he can ever do that will
change that
I've struggled for years worrying about
being good enough this is me talking
about me growing up I was taught that
unless I had unquestioning obedience and
I was performed perfectly I was not
worthy of Love or worthy of my dreams or
goals to manifest
and that I must constantly prove my
right standing both with God and other
people or be punished harshly
and I ref and I and I just made this the
stand I refuse to continue this toxic
Trend with my child or family ever
um you know this this behavior is not
okay it's not serving us this way of
thinking turns adults
and we constantly try to defend
ourselves and prove that we're worthy of
our desires
well the truth is just like my baby boy
we are and always have been good enough
no matter what we do or perform did you
know that you can repair it yourself did
you know that you can change the pattern
of how you were raised as an adult I
know I did give yourself compassion that
the same compassion that you would give
to a child when they make a mistake as
if you were the parent you needed not
the one you had
yeah quit trying to prove and I've I've
done a lot of what has helped me before
I found Parts work was this inner child
healing so some of what I teach comes
from that inner child healing Parts work
takes that and takes it to like level
ten thousand it's amazing yeah so give
yourself the compassion that you would
give a child quit trying to prove that
you're in right standing or are worthy
of love you're perfect just as you are
right now
fully worthy of everything that you
could ever imagine nothing inside or
outside of you has to change for that to
be true
give yourself a big hug and a high five
today for how amazing you are start
believing that you're absolutely
incredible the badass amazing version of
yourself that you've always dreamed of
and wanted to be you are right now
that kind of household is a household
that my baby boy is going to grow up and
I'm so excited for his future whatever
desires and dreams they might be
he will always be perfect just as he is
with nothing that has to change he'll
accept and love himself unconditionally
even when he makes big mistakes and
messes and that's what I would invite
you guys if you're listening to this to
do is start to accept yourself give
yourself a high five and a hug with
compassion even when you make those
bigger mistakes and those messes you're
worthy of every dream that you have
you're good enough just as you are in
fact you're beyond good enough you're
absolutely incredible and amazing you
are not less than perfect you're not you
are just how you are right now is
incredible is awesome I think we tend to
talk about ourselves like we're broken
when in fact there's no broken or bad
parts we're just putting that all
together start loving yourself with that
same compassion that you would a baby
child and a growing child and give
yourself that love it's going to change
everything for you
you know and so Venice like any final
words or final thoughts for people as we
close out as we wrap up this podcast
my final words would be just an echo of
what you're saying which is you are
whole complete and perfect right now yep
and no there's some things in the way
and it's your Humanity but at the core
who you really are is whole complete
perfect not broken wow and I encourage
you to get connected to you know
communities such as Jeremiah's I'm not a
business coach but I love working with
people get connected to people who can
speak into your life in a way that
expands that because it will make a
difference and the last thing is I mean
I've known you years Jeremiah and I just
acknowledge you for your courage and all
the grit and how you've made a
difference and you're very Relentless
thank you you've made a difference in my
life and I know you make a difference in
the lives of others so thank you and I'm
just really excited to see you continue
to grow I'm excited we're going to grow
together bro too yeah listen if you need
that voice in your life maybe you're
looking for somebody a life coach or
somebody to help you organize those
thoughts in your life and help you kind
of integrate those parts that's what
Venice is helping people do that's how
she's being of service to the world and
here's something I want you to remember
is you know your life can have a Major
Impact if just one person had a positive
impact on a thousand people who then had
an impact on a thousand other people and
those thousand people impacted a
thousand others you your life would
touch 1 8 of the entire world's
population
it's over a billion people right there
and so realize that like just little me
like we think little of me what can I do
you can do a whole lot you can do as
much or as little as you want too and
that's what's awesome like like there's
nobody's like goals for their business
are better or worse than each other my
goals are pretty big like I ain't stop
until I get to the billions
at all and I ain't slowing down when I
get there either until at 10 and 100 and
that like that's where that's where I'm
going the trajectory of my life an
impact but it starts with this
Foundation that we're talking about
right now when you start on the good
foundation this good foundation will
take you beyond where you could ever
imagine
great all right thanks for being here
Venice this has been amazing God bless
have a good one everybody listen if this
has helped you if this episode has
helped share it with somebody don't hold
this bin don't hold it to yourself share
it with your friends your family let
them know this work might just change
somebody else's life as well
talk soon
[Music]